Teacher's Lounge
（麻耶）創設祭の準備なんだけど
予定より遅れてるみたいね
About the Founder's Festival preparations...
It looks like things are running behind schedule.
Will you be okay?
大丈夫？
（詞）平気です
We'll be fine.
It's true that things are running a little slow, but we can still make up for the lost time.
確かに遅れ気味ではありますけど
まだ　ばん回は可能ですから
I see.
そう　あのね　絢辻さん
Listen, Ayatsuji-san...
あなた　この間
倒れちゃったでしょ
Didn't you collapse the other day?
Yes, but...
はい　でも…
We discussed the issue in the last staff meeting.
それが職員会議で
少し問題になってね
創設祭の規模を小さくしてみては
どうかって話が出たの
It was suggested that we could do a little less for this year's Founder's Festival.
For example, we could forego lighting the
Christmas tree or reduce the number of events.
例えばクリスマスツリーのイルミネーションを
なくしたり
イベントの数を減らすとか…
平気です！
We'll be fine!
絢辻さん
A-Ayatsuji-san...
実行委員のみんなも一生懸命
努力してくれていますから
Everyone in the committee is trying their absolute best to help.
もう少し見守って
いただけないでしょうか？
Could you wait a little longer and see what happens?
よろしくお願いします
Please.
All right.  However...
分かったわ　ただし
無理だけはしないこと　いいわね？
Don't overwork yourself.
Got that?
はい　分かりました
Okay.  I understand.
・～
Kimi wa kimi no mama de
You just being you
君は君のままで
Boku wa boku no mama de
And me just being me
僕は僕のままで
Subete wakariaetara
If we could understand each other completely
全て分かり合えたら
UTW Presents
Amagami
SS
UTW Presents
Amagami
SS
Nando mo kisetsu wo kasaneta ne ano hi kara
The seasons have come and gone since that day
何度も季節を重ねたね　あの日から
Kyou made doumo arigatou
And even today, I remain so grateful
今日までどうもありがとう
Semai rojiura mezashi
We head towards a narrow back alley
狭い路地裏目指し
Shiroi iki ga odoru
As our white breaths dance in the air
白い息が踊る
Itai kurai nigitta te wo hiite
You hold me by the hand so hard it almost hurts
痛いくらい握った手をひいて
まったく…　屈辱よ　屈辱だわ
Kimi wa susunde yuku
And pull me with you as you walk on forward
君は進んでいく
Ima sugu kisu shitakatta
I wanted to kiss you right then
今すぐキスしたかった
この私が呼び出されて
注意を受けるなんて
Kakureta jihanki no ura
Hidden behind the vending machines
隠れた自販機の裏
（純一）ははははッ
それで何を言われたの？
Hanikande mitsumeatta
We shyly gazed at each other
ハニかんで見つめあった
みんながもっと
しっかりしてくれれば
こんな苦労しなくて済むのに
Yasashii kimochi afureta
And I was overcome with kind feelings for you
優しいキモチ溢れた
すみません
別にあなたを
責めてるわけじゃないけど
Kimi wa kimi no mama de
You just being you
君は君のままで
スケジュールが遅れてるって
言われたわ
Boku wa boku no mama de
And me just being me
僕は僕のままで
えッ？
クリスマスツリーのイルミネーションは
Subete wakariaeta nara
If we could understand each other completely
全て分かり合えたなら
なくした方が
いいんじゃないかって
そんなの絶対イヤよ
Futari wa hitotsu da yo
The two of us would become one
２人は１つだよ
Donna chiisa na shiawase mo
No matter how small it may be
どんな小さな幸せも
うん　そうだね
みんなも楽しみにしてるだろうし
Mitsukedaseru ki ga suru yo
We'll surely find happiness
見つけ出せる気がするよ
僕も精一杯　協力するよ
ありがとう
Yasashiku nareta no wa kimi no okage
I learned to be kind because of you
優しくなれたのは　君のおかげ
Founder's Festival Planning
Committee Headquarters
Damn it.
That was humiliating.  Really humiliating.
I can't believe I was called in and coached like that...
So what did she say to you?
I wouldn't have to suffer like this if
everyone else had their act together.
Sorry.
I'm not saying it's your fault.
She said that we're behind schedule.
She also suggested that we forget about lighting the Christmas tree this year.
There's no way I'd accept that.
Ayatsuji Tsukasa Arc
Chapter 3
Pride
Yeah, you're right.
Everyone's also looking forward to it.
I'll do everything I can to help!
Thanks.
でもね…
まだ何かあるの？
But still...
Is there something else?
時間が足りないのも事実なのよね
It's true that we don't have enough time.
ねえ　あなた　何か…
Hey you, can you think of-
（扉が開く）
Excuse me, Tachibana-senpai.
すみません　橘先輩
えッ　僕？
Huh?  Me?
メインステージで使うライトを
捜してるんですけど
I was looking for the main stage lights, but I can't seem to find them.
見つからなくて
Ah, they should be in the supply room.
ああ　それなら資材倉庫で見たよ
でも　少し重たいからな
But they might be a little heavy.
橘君　こっちは１人で大丈夫だから
手伝ってあげて
Tachibana-kun.
I'll be fine by myself here, so go help them out.
いいの？
ええ
You sure?
Yeah.
はい　鍵
ありがとう
Here's the key.
Thanks.
じゃあ　行ってくるね
Okay, I'll be back.
行ってらっしゃい
See you.
（美也）昨日　まんま肉まん
食べすぎちゃってさ
So I had too many meat buns yesterday...
あれから一晩　考えてみたの
I thought about what to do with the lack of time all night yesterday.
残り少ない時間でどうするか
But I couldn't come up with any good ideas...
でも　なかなか
いいアイデアが浮かばなくて
ねえ　何かない？
Hey, any suggestions?
しまらない顔してどうしたのよ？
What's with that stupid look on your face?
I mean, I didn't expect you to make lunch for me...
だって絢辻さんが僕のために
お弁当を作ってきてくれるなんて
I'm so happy.
嬉しくて
Mmm, delicious!  It's incredible!
う～ん　おいしい　最高だよ
犬が芸をしたら
ご褒美をあげるものでしょう？
You reward your dogs when they perform tricks.
I'm just rewarding you in advance.
これは　その前払いよ
僕は犬ですか
So I'm a dog now?
それよりアイデアよ　何かない？
More importantly, I need ideas.
Any suggestions?
う～ん　そうだね
Hmm, let's see.
やっぱり人を増やすのが
一番だと思うけど
I think it'd be best to have more people help out.
No way.
それはダメ
どうして？
Why not?
みっともないじゃないの
Because it's pathetic!
Am I supposed to say, "we just realized we need more people, so please help us"?
今さら人手が足りませんでした
手伝ってください　なんて
My pride won't allow that.
私のプライドが許さないわ
But we won't make it on time at this rate.
でも　このままじゃ
間に合わないんでしょ？
僕達　実行委員だけで
頑張ってもいいけど
I see why you'd want to keep the work to committee members...
無理はするなって
言われてるんだし
But we were told not to overwork ourselves.
I think it's best if we play it safe.
ここは正攻法が
一番なんじゃないかな
それに
大勢に手伝ってもらったとしても
Besides, even if we pull in a whole crowd of people to help,
I'm sure that it'll still improve your standing as long as the festival is successful.
それをまとめて
創設祭を成功させれば
絢辻さんの評価も上がると思うよ
Your ability to lead, that is.
統率力という部分で
統率力…
Ability to lead...
Yeah.  Well?
うん　どうかな？
Fine.  Not like I have a choice anyway.
分かったわ　それしかないみたいね
Great.
よかった　じゃあとりあえず
僕達のクラスから協力を頼もうか
So let's start with asking our class to help.
Yeah.
そうね　でもその前に…
But before that...
その前に？
Before that?
人を増やすアイデアは
私も考えてたし
Since I also did consider getting more people...
I'll take this.
だから　これは没収ね
ああッ
からあげは　とっておいたのに
I was saving the fried chicken for last!
I already ate it, so you're not getting it back~
もう食べちゃったから
返せませーん
そんなあ
No fair...
Hey, look.
（やよい）ねえ　あれ
Hmm?
（ゆーこ）うん？→
Ayatsuji-san and Tachibana-kun?
絢辻さんと橘君？
・（やよい）だね
・（みゆき）ああ…
Yeah.
Hmm...
・～
（やよい）あ～あ　やってらんない
Ugh, I've had enough.
ホント　何で私達が
こんなことしなきゃいけないの？
Yeah, right?  Why do we have to do this anyway?
（みゆき）あの２人が委員やるって
自分から立候補したくせに
Those two were the ones who volunteered to be in the committee, not us!
こっちに
迷惑かけないでほしいよね
I'd rather they didn't trouble us too.
２人でイチャイチャするのに
忙しいんだよ
I'm sure they're too busy flirting with each other.
（ざわつく生徒達）
私達　見ちゃったんだよね
We saw them do it.
Ayatsuji-san and Tachibana-kun looked real close having lunch together.
絢辻さんと橘君が
昼休みに仲良くお弁当食べてるの
うんうん
Yeah.
ごめん　会議で遅くなっちゃった
Sorry, we're late because of the meeting.
Huh?
ああ？　みんな　どうしたの？
What's the matter, guys?
何か問題でもあった？
Is there a problem?
I heard that we aren't doing a
Christmas tree this year.  Is that true?
・（やよい）クリスマスツリーが
中止になるって聞いたけどホント？
去年より派手な
創設祭の計画を立てて
You made all these plans for an even grander Festival than last year's.
それが　うまくいきそうにないから
But now you're making everyone help because things aren't going well?  What gives?
今さら　みんなを手伝わせるって
どういうつもり？
So you'll take all the credit as committee president if things go smoothly?
成功したら実行委員長の
絢辻さんの手柄にするつもり？
ずいぶんと都合がよすぎない？
Aren't you having it a little too good?
I wasn't planning anything like that...
別にそんなつもりは…
スケジュールが遅れてるのは　誰かさんが
男子とイチャイチャしてるせいでしょ？
Aren't we behind schedule because
somebody was flirting around with a guy?
私　聞いたよ　いつも
２人っきりで仕事してるって→
I know all about it.
You two are always alone together when you work.
Just like a couple.
彼氏彼女みたいにさ
それは…
T-That's...
橘君には　私の補佐的な
仕事をしてもらってるから
Tachibana-kun has been assisting me with my work, so we may have given off the wrong impression.
そういう誤解を
与えてしまうのかもしれないけど
But we haven't done anything except work.
別に仕事以外のことを
してるわけじゃないわ
I don't believe that.
そんなの信用できない
うんうん
Yeah.
（薫）ちょっと！　あんた達ねえ
Hey!
Really, you girls...
You shut up, Tanamachi-san.
・（やよい）棚町さんは黙ってて
You're mistaken.
誤解だよ　絢辻さんは手際が悪い
僕に色々教えてくれてるだけで…
Ayatsuji-san was just helping me out because I'm inexperienced...
I wasn't asking you either!
あんたにも聞いてない
Ow...
イテテテ
・（やよい）どうなの？　絢辻さん
何とか言いなさいよ
Well, Ayatsuji-san?
Say something.
ヤバッ
もしかして泣かせちゃった？
Uh oh, did we make her cry?
フッ
絢辻さん？
Ayatsuji-san?
フフフフッ
アハハハハハッ
（詞の高笑い）
絢辻さん？
Ayatsuji-san?
フン
Ahh, this is stupid.
あ～あ　バカバカしい
What does any of this have to do with the Founder's Festival?
あなた達の言ってることは
創設祭に
関係のないことばかりじゃない
What's the matter?  You jealous?
何それ　もしかして嫉妬？
いいこと教えてあげる
I'll tell you something.
クリスマスツリーは中止にならないし
The Christmas Tree isn't going anywhere.
スケジュールだって去年に比べて
The schedule is on track to go just as smoothly as last year.
十分に間に合うペースなの
And the purpose of having all of you help is to assure that.
みんなに手伝ってもらうのは
それを確実にするため
I can show you all the data if you don't believe me.
信用できないなら　いくらでも
資料を見せてあげるわよ
いるのよね～　あなた達みたいに
So people like you who spread baseless rumors and do nothing but complain really exist!
根も葉もない噂をうのみにして
文句ばかり言う人
何もできないくせに他人を見下し
優越感にひたるなんて　くだらない
You look down on others to feel superior even though you can't do anything on your own.  How pathetic!
言い返したかったら　どうぞ
Go ahead if you want to respond.
でも　何ができるの？
何をやってきたの？
But what can any of you do?
What have you accomplished?
Do you really think there's anything about you that's better than me?
何か一つでも
私に勝てるところがある？
恥って言葉を知ってるなら
If you know the meaning of the word "shame"...
自分の人生を
振り返ってからにしてよね
Come back after you've taken a good look at your own lives.
さあ　何か言いたいことが
あったらどうぞ
Now, be my guest if you have anything to say.
Nothing?
何もないの？　だったら最初から
つまらないこと言ってないで
Then you shouldn't have opened your mouth in the first place.
You should get some work done instead.
手だけ動かしてればいいのよ
That's all the lot of you are capable of anyway.
どうせ　あなた達には
それしかできないんだから
〈絢辻さん…〉
Ayatsuji-san...
あれは
さすがに言い過ぎじゃないかな
I think you might've gone a little too far there...
Ayatsuji-san?
絢辻さん？
ねえ　これ覚えてる？
Hey, do you remember this?
えッ？　ああ　うん　覚えてるけど
Yeah, I do.
Good.
そう
絢辻さん　何してるんだよ！？
Ayatsuji-san, what are you doing?!
いいの
It's fine.
私には　もう必要のないものだから
I don't need this anymore.
I've realized that I now have something more important.
私にはもっと
大切なものがあるって分かったの
聞いてくれる？
うん
Will you listen?
Yeah.
あなたを私のものにします
I want you to become mine.
はあ？
Huh?!
Huh?  Did I skip a few steps?
あれ？　ちょっと
はしょりすぎたかしら
A few?  You skipped a lot!
ちょっとどころじゃなくて
相当だよ
What do you mean, become yours?
私のものにするって
どういうこと？
I-I have fun and am happy when I'm with you.
あなたといると　嬉しいし楽しいの
Well... to the point where I can barely understand it.
その…　自分でも不思議なくらい
できれば　ずっと一緒にいたい
I want to be with you forever if I can.
It's enough for me if you'll stay by my side.
あなたが　そばにいてくれれば十分
でも　それを強制はできない
But I can't force you to.
That's why I'll give myself to you.
だから　私をあげる
その代わり　今あなたがいる日常を
私にちょうだい
In exchange, give me days filled with you!
僕なんかでいいの？
Are you sure you want someone like me?
I won't say it again.
２回は言わない　はっきり答えて
Give me a clear answer.
不安でいっぱいなんだから
うん
I'm pretty anxious right now, so...
Okay.
If you'll have me...
僕でよければ　喜んで
I'm gladly yours.
I see.
そう
じゃあ　これは契約の証し
This will serve as proof of the agreement.
ええッ！？
いつでもいいわよ
Whenever you're ready.
うッ　うん
O-Okay.
これで契約成立ね
うん
Now the agreement has been made.
Yeah.
I was... a little nervous.
ちょっと　緊張しちゃった
僕もだよ
Me too.
さあ　火の後始末をして
帰りましょう
All right, let's clean up the ashes and head home.
うん
Okay.
あッ　絢辻さん
Ayatsuji-san!
何？
ええと　鼻…
What?
Uh... your nose.
My nose?
鼻？
えッ？
絢辻さんでも興奮するんだね
Ayatsuji-san, looks like even you get excited sometimes.
Ouch!
イッタ～ッ！
うう～　まだヒリヒリする
It still stings...
おはよう
Morning.
ハハハハッ
はあ…
おはよう
Morning.
絢辻さん　おはよう
Ayatsuji-san, morning.
Did you put together the data we'll be using for today's committee meeting?
今日の実行委員会議で使う資料
まとめてきてくれた？
Y-Yeah.  I did.
ああ　うん　やってきたよ
ありがとう
Thanks.
〈用事があるから
とりあえず１０周走っとけって〉
"Something came up, so just run ten rounds for now."
〈いくらなんでも先生
手抜きすぎじゃないか？〉
I don't know what happened, Sensei,
but aren't you slacking a little too much?
Huh?
あれ？
（梅原）やっと気づいたか
So you finally noticed.
Is Ayatsuji-san's team losing?
絢辻さんのチーム　負けてるのか？
She's the only one left in the court.
内野が１人しかいないよ
じゃなくて
No, it seems like she was on her own to begin with.
最初から１人だけみたいだぜ
ええッ？
Huh?
そういうことだ
That's exactly what's happening.
僕　先に行くよ
早く１０周　終わらせなきゃ
I'll go on ahead.
I've gotta finish my ten rounds quickly!
Yeah, go for it!
おう　頑張れよ
Hey, Kanae-chan.
（梨穂子）ねえ　香苗ちゃん　あれ…
Look.
（香苗）えッ？
It looks like there's trouble in the game next to ours.
お隣さん　なんか
面倒なことになってるみたいね
ほらほら　どうしたの？
もうヘバっちゃった？
Come on now, what's the matter?
You tired already?
まだ　やる気十分ね
Looks like you won't be giving up anytime soon.
さあ　棚町さん　やっちゃって
All right, Tanamachi-san, go for it.
I'll pass.
私　パス
えッ？
Huh?
Well, being in this team is boring.
だって　このチーム
つまんないんだもん
ということで私
こっちのチームに入るね
So I'll be joining this team.
ちょっと　棚町さん？
Wait, Tanamachi-san!
別に助っ人なんていらないのに
I don't really need a teammate.
そんなこと言わないで
私にも少しは楽しませてよ
Don't say that.
Let me have some fun at least.
ほら恵子　あんたもこっち来なさい
Hey, Keiko!
Come over to this side too!
（恵子）えッ？　うん…
O-Okay...
これで３人ね
いや　４人だよ
Now we have three people.
No, four people!
えッ？　橘君
Tachibana-kun!
いいでしょ？　絢辻さん
Is that okay, Ayatsuji-san?
ちょっと！　どうしてあんたが
女子のドッジボールに割り込むのよ
Wait, why are you barging into the girls' dodgeball game?!
I've already finished running the assigned ten laps.
課題の１０周
もう走り終わっちゃったんだよね
I'm kinda bored, so I was wondering if I could join in.
退屈だから
少し交ぜてもらおうと思って
You seem really out of breath though.
めちゃめちゃ息上がってるけど
あはははッ　カッコイ～！
You're so cool!
カッコイイよ　純一
そりゃ　どうも
You're really cool, Junichi!
Thank you.
Hey, Tachibana!
おい橘　お前　速すぎ
You're way too fast!
ねえ　どうする？
Hey, what should we do?
If you guys wanna play that much,
then play by yourselves all you want!
そんなにやりたいなら
あんた達だけで
やってればいいじゃない
Huh?  That's it?
あれ終わり？　つまんないの
That's lame.
ヘッヘッヘッ
So we've at least ordered everything we need.
とりあえず
必要なものは全部注文したのね
Yeah.
うん　あとは到着を待つだけだよ
We just have to wait for their delivery now.
So that's another job taken care of.
これで　また一つ
仕事が片づいたわね
Yeah.
そうだね
お待たせ　あッ
Sorry we took so long... huh?
他の人達は？
帰っちゃった
Where's everyone?
They all went home.
They said they had stuff to do...
みんな用事があるとかで
そっか
I see.
まあいいわ
少数精鋭って言葉もあるし
Well, that's fine.
It's better to have a small but skilled team anyway.
私達だけでやりましょう
Let's do the work ourselves!
おうよ　帰っちまった連中の分まで
俺がビシッと働いてやるぜ
That's right!
I'll handle all the work those home-goers were supposed to do!
Talking big again?
おッ　言うわね
俺は　やるときゃやるぜ
I get stuff done when I actually try.
ほれるなよ
ほらほら　おしゃべりはそこまで
Don't fall in love.
Okay okay, that's enough talk.
Kibitou High School
Founder's Festival
Let's begin.
始めるわよ
・（梅原）おう
Yeah.
Okay!
・（薫）は～い
Ahh, I'm so tired!
ああ疲れた～ッ
I don't think I've stayed behind at school this late before.
俺　こんな時間まで学校にいたの
初めてかも
Hey, you guys wanna go somewhere?
ねえ　これから
どっか寄ってかない？
Huh?
You serious?
マジかよ　俺はもうクタクタだぜ
I'm totally exhausted!
Exactly, we should be going home!
・（恵子）そうだよ　早く帰ろうよ
Ayatsuji-san?
絢辻さん？　どうかしたの？
What's the matter?
教室に忘れ物したみたい
ちょっと取ってくるわ
Looks like I left something in the classroom.
I'm gonna go get it.
Want me to come with you?
一緒に行こうか？
No, it's fine, so head home first.
ううん　大丈夫だから
先に帰ってて
うん
Okay.
I'm fine.
大丈夫　私は平気
I'm doing okay.
まだ頑張れる　でも…
I can still do it.
But...
絢辻さん
Ayatsuji-san.
やっぱり１人で作業してたんだ
So you really are working by yourself again.
Tachibana-kun.
橘君
I would've helped if you had just asked.
言ってくれれば僕も手伝うのに
絢辻さん？
Ayatsuji-san?
ありがとう　もう大丈夫
Thanks.  I'm fine now.
大丈夫って？
You're fine?
You know...
あのさ　やっぱり
もう一度みんなに頼んで
Don't you think we should ask for everyone's help again?
手伝ってもらった方が
いいんじゃないかな？
Huh?
えッ？　それ本気で言ってるの？
Are you being serious?
Well, we won't make it at this rate.
だって
このままじゃ間に合わないよ
梅原君達が手伝ってくれてるわ
Umehara-kun and the others are helping already.
But I'm sure you know their help alone isn't enough!
それでも手が足りてないことは
分かってるでしょ
I'll work all night... I'll do anything if it comes down to it!
そのときは
私が徹夜でも何でもするわよ
And what if you collapse again?!
それで　また倒れたらどうするの？
Anyway, I won't ask for help.
とにかく　絶対にイヤ
Why not?!
どうしたんだよ
そんなの　らしくないよ
That's not like you!
That's not like me?
らしくない？
そうだよ
That's right!
絢辻さんは
いつももっと堂々としてて
Ayatsuji-san, aren't you someone who
confidently handles situations like this?!
こんな状況　いくらでも
うまく切り抜けられる人だろ
ううん　ホントは
こんな状況になる前にもっと…
Actually, you'd take care of it before it even-
What do you mean, not like me?!
らしくないって何？
You think you know anything about me?!
あなたが私の何を分かってるの？
Hey, I'm asking you what you think you know!
ねえ　何を分かってるっていうの！？
But I do know.
分かってるよ
I know that you're giving it your all for the Founder's Festival, Ayatsuji-san.
絢辻さんが創設祭に
一生懸命なのは分かってるよ
だからさ　みんなに謝って
That's why you should apologize to
everyone and ask for their help again.
もう一度手伝ってくれるように
頼もう
If you don't want to, we could try to scrap some of the events...
それがイヤなら　できる範囲で
少しイベントを減らすとかさ
イタッ
Ow... huh?
何で…　何で分かってるのに
Why?
Why do you say things like that even though you know?
そんなこと言うのよ
・（ゆーこ）こっちを使った方が
見た目　派手じゃない？
Wouldn't it look better if you used these here instead?
えッ？
Nobody can see what's on top of the tree anyway,
ツリーの上は　どうせ見えないから
電飾とモールだけにしたら？
so why not hang just the lights and the tinsel there?
そうすれば飾りつけとかも
楽だもんね
This way, decorating the tree will be a breeze!
その分　人形を下に飾れば
子供も喜ぶんじゃないかな
You can then hang the dolls on the lower part, which I'm sure the kids will love!
Yeah, you're right!
うん　そうだね
Thank you!
ありがとう
みんなに相談してよかった
I'm so glad I discussed this with you!
〈どうなってるんだ？〉
What's going on?
Good morning!
グッモーニン
ああ　薫
Ah, Kaoru.
What's that about?
何だ　あれ？
うん？　ああ　あれね
Oh, that?
私も実際に
見てたわけじゃないんだけど…
I didn't actually see it happen, but...
I'm sorry!
《ごめんなさい》
Why the apology?
《何よ　いきなり　何のつもり？》
What do you want?
《この前　私　言いすぎたから》
I went a little too far the other day...
I'm really sorry!
《本当にごめんなさい》
And... well...
《あのう　それで》
《もし許してもらえるなら》
If you'll forgive me, I'd really like your help with the Founder's Festival...
《創設祭の手伝い
やっぱりお願いしたくて》
《はあ？　何言ってんの　あんた》
Huh?!
What the heck are you talking about?!
Even after you said all that?!
《あれだけのことを言ったくせに》
《謝っても許さないよ》
We won't forgive you with just an apology!
I'm... really sorry...
《本当にごめんなさい》
《でも私　創設祭を成功させたくて》
But...
I really want this Founder's Festival to be successful...
I was hoping everyone would have fun preparing for it...
《みんなで楽しく準備できたらって
思って　それで…》
And so...
《・（クラスメイト達）
何あれ？　泣かしてんの？》
What's that?
Did they make her cry?
《絢辻さんも言いすぎたけど
あいつらもなあ》
Ayatsuji-san may have gone too far, but as for them...
《ああ　体育のときな》
Yeah, during PE, right?
《・（女子）謝ってるんだから
許せばいいのに》
She already apologized, so why not just forgive her?
《分かった　分かったから》
Yeah, okay, I get it!
《私達も言いすぎた》
We went too far as well.
《創設祭の準備　手伝うから》
We'll help you prepare for the Founder's Festival.
Look up, okay?
《顔上げて　ねえ》
《本当？》
《ホント　ホント　約束する》
Really?
Yeah, really.
I promise.
《ありがとう》
Thank you!
…っていうことなんだって
And that's what happened.
嘘だろ
That's gotta be a lie!
嘘のようなホントの話らしいわよ
It sounds like one, but that's apparently what happened.
あッ　おはよう　橘君
Morning, Tachibana-kun.
おはよう
聞いて　聞いて
Morning.
Listen to this!
Everyone said they'll help prepare for the Founder's Festival!
みんな創設祭の準備
手伝ってくれるって
I see.
そう…
うん　みんな優しいね
Yeah, everyone's so kind!
I'm so glad I'm in this class!
私　このクラスになれてよかった
なあに？
こんなところに呼び出して
So what did you call me out here for?
Don't tell me...
もしかして　また　キスとか？
You want to kiss again?
That's not it!
違うよ　それも魅力的だけどさ
Though that does sound pretty attractive.
Anyway, what on Earth happened?!
それより　一体どうしちゃったの？
Huh?  What?
えッ　何が？
Weren't you really against asking the rest of the class for help yesterday?
昨日はクラスのみんなに
手伝ってもらうの
あんなに嫌がっていたじゃないか
Didn't you slap me for suggesting that?
それで僕のこと　ひっぱたいただろ
What are you talking about?
何のこと？
何のことって…
You're asking me?
あッ　もしかして　あの子のことを
言ってるのかな
Ah, could you be talking about that girl?
That girl?
あの子？
That stubborn girl who was ready to do anything to prepare for the Founder's Festival alone.
いこじになって
１人で創設際の準備を
なんとか間に合わせようとしてた
あの子
But that girl you once knew doesn't exist anymore.
でも　もうあなたの知ってる
あの子は　いなくなっちゃったの
えッ？
おかげでみんな
協力してくれることになったし
And thanks to that, everyone's giving us their help.
This way, the Founder's Festival will surely be a huge success!
これで創設祭の大成功
間違いなしだね
フフフフッ
What on Earth happened to her?!
〈一体　どうなってるんだよ？〉
・～
Hodou wo kazaru aoi Illumination
The blue illumination adorns the sidewalk
歩道を飾る　青いイルミネーション
Nigiwau hitogomi ni hitori tatazumu
And I stand alone in the swarming crowd
にぎわう人込みにひとりたたずむ
Koboresou na egao
Smiles peeking through
こぼれそうな笑顔
Yorisou koibitotachi
Lovers snuggling against each other
寄り添う恋人達
Ima no watashi ni wa subete ga
Everything to me now is so bright
今の私には全てが
Mabushikute mirenai no
That I cannot bear to look
まぶしくて見れないの
Dareka ni aisareru deshou ka
Will anyone love me?
誰かに愛されるでしょうか
Tsuyogari no oku ni kakureta
I'm hiding underneath a facade
強がりの奥に隠れた
Watashi ni kizuite yo
Please realize that
「わたし」に気付いてよ
Hontou ni jiyuu ni nareru deshou ka
Can I really become free?
本当に自由になれるでしょうか
Douka oshiete
Please tell me
どうか教えて
Fuyu no machi ni mayoikonda
Having lost her way in the winter town
冬の町に迷い込んだ
Samishige na tenshi ga nageku
The lonely angel sighs
さみしげな　天使が嘆く
Yasashiku
Gently
優しく
Preview
Next episode preview.
Tachibana-kun, just a little more to go until the Founder's Festival!
Yeah, you're right.
I also made up with everyone in the class,
so I'm sure the preparations for the Founder's Festival will go well!
Yeah.
Let's have a wonderful Founder's Festival.
Christmas Eve is approaching once again...
Next episode: "Promise".
Next Episode
Promise
Where did the Ayatsuji-san I fell in love with go?
I am me.
I am... me.